/**
 * Author: @Manuel G. Sintos
 * Date: Nov 27, 2023, 1:11 PM
 *
 */

const data_02 = [
	{
	    id: 0,
	    question: "Which Philippine law primarily focuses on environmental protection and conservation?",
	    choices: [
	        "Republic Act No. 10175 (Cybercrime Prevention Act)",
	        "Republic Act No. 9165 (Comprehensive Dangerous Drugs Act)",
	        "Republic Act No. 8749 (Philippine Clean Air Act)",
	        "Republic Act No. 10951 (Penalizing the Act of Hazing)",
	        "Republic Act No. 8353 (Anti-Rape Law)"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Republic Act No. 8749 (Philippine Clean Air Act)",
	    explanation: "Republic Act No. 8749, also known as the Philippine Clean Air Act, primarily focuses on environmental protection by addressing air quality management and pollution control to safeguard public health and the environment from air pollution.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
    id: 1,
	    question: "Which Philippine law addresses proper waste disposal and recycling to minimize the environmental impact of solid waste?",
	    choices: [
	        "Republic Act No. 10175 (Cybercrime Prevention Act)",
	        "Republic Act No. 9165 (Comprehensive Dangerous Drugs Act)",
	        "Republic Act No. 8749 (Philippine Clean Air Act)",
	        "Republic Act No. 9003 (Ecological Solid Waste Management Act of 2000)",
	        "Republic Act No. 8353 (Anti-Rape Law)"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Republic Act No. 9003 (Ecological Solid Waste Management Act of 2000)",
	    explanation: "Republic Act No. 9003, known as the Ecological Solid Waste Management Act of 2000, addresses proper waste disposal and recycling to minimize the environmental impact of solid waste.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 2,
	    question: "Which Philippine law regulates the discharge of pollutants into water bodies to protect water resources?",
	    choices: [
	        "Republic Act No. 10175 (Cybercrime Prevention Act)",
	        "Republic Act No. 9165 (Comprehensive Dangerous Drugs Act)",
	        "Republic Act No. 8749 (Philippine Clean Air Act)",
	        "Republic Act No. 10951 (Penalizing the Act of Hazing)",
	        "Republic Act No. 9275 (Philippine Clean Water Act of 2004)"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Republic Act No. 9275 (Philippine Clean Water Act of 2004)",
	    explanation: "Republic Act No. 9275, known as the Philippine Clean Water Act of 2004, regulates the discharge of pollutants into water bodies to protect water resources.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 3,
	    question: "Which international agreement aims to guide the Philippines in biodiversity conservation?",
	    choices: [
	        "Kyoto Protocol",
	        "Montreal Protocol",
	        "Convention on Biological Diversity",
	        "Paris Agreement",
	        "United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Convention on Biological Diversity",
	    explanation: "The Convention on Biological Diversity is an international agreement that guides the Philippines in biodiversity conservation and sustainable use of biological resources.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 4,
	    question: "What is the primary goal of the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change for the Philippines?",
	    choices: [
	        "Promote the use of fossil fuels",
	        "Reduce greenhouse gas emissions",
	        "Encourage deforestation",
	        "Increase water pollution",
	        "Support industrial pollution"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Reduce greenhouse gas emissions",
	    explanation: "The primary goal of the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change for the Philippines is to reduce greenhouse gas emissions and mitigate the impacts of climate change.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 5,
	    question: "Which government agency is primarily responsible for enforcing environmental laws in the Philippines?",
	    choices: [
	        "Department of Education",
	        "Department of Transportation",
	        "Environmental Management Bureau (EMB)",
	        "Department of Agriculture",
	        "Department of Trade and Industry"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Environmental Management Bureau (EMB)",
	    explanation: "The DENR or Environmental Management Bureau (EMB) is primarily responsible for enforcing environmental laws and regulations in the Philippines.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 6,
	    question: "Which source of energy in the Philippines contributes to reducing greenhouse gas emissions and dependence on fossil fuels?",
	    choices: [
	        "Coal",
	        "Natural gas",
	        "Renewable energy sources",
	        "Diesel",
	        "Nuclear energy"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Renewable energy sources",
	    explanation: "Renewable energy sources like solar, wind, and hydroelectric power in the Philippines reduce greenhouse gas emissions and dependence on fossil fuels, promoting environmental conservation.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 7,
	    question: "How does waste segregation and recycling programs contribute to environmental conservation in the Philippines?",
	    choices: [
	        "Increasing landfill waste",
	        "Promoting waste incineration",
	        "Minimizing waste and promoting a sustainable approach",
	        "Encouraging illegal dumping",
	        "Boosting plastic production"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Minimizing waste and promoting a sustainable approach",
	    explanation: "Waste segregation and recycling programs help minimize waste sent to landfills and promote sustainable waste management practices.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 8,
	    question: "What is the term for the practice of planting native trees and restoring deforested areas in the Philippines?",
	    choices: [
	        "Urbanization",
	        "Afforestation",
	        "Reforestation",
	        "Desertification",
	        "Deforestation"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Reforestation",
	    explanation: "Reforestation involves planting native trees and restoring deforested areas in the Philippines, contributing to conservation efforts.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 9,
	    question: "Which initiative in the Philippines aims to reduce plastic pollution and promote sustainable alternatives?",
	    choices: [
	        "Banning the use of glass bottles",
	        "Promoting single-use plastics",
	        "Banning Single-Use Plastics",
	        "Encouraging plastic bag usage",
	        "Implementing disposable plastic tax"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Banning Single-Use Plastics",
	    explanation: "The Philippines has implemented measures to ban single-use plastics in an effort to reduce plastic pollution and encourage sustainable alternatives.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 10,
	    question: "What is the primary goal of marine protected areas (MPAs) in the Philippines?",
	    choices: [
	        "Promoting recreational fishing",
	        "Protecting marine biodiversity and ecosystems",
	        "Encouraging industrial fishing",
	        "Establishing offshore drilling sites",
	        "Enhancing tourism infrastructure"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Protecting marine biodiversity and ecosystems",
	    explanation: "The primary purpose of MPAs in the Philippines is to protect marine biodiversity and ecosystems by restricting human activities that could harm them.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 11,
	    question: "What international agreement, aimed at combating climate change, set targets for reducing greenhouse gas emissions, with a goal of limiting global warming to well below 2 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels?",
	    choices: [
	        "Kyoto Protocol",
	        "Paris Agreement",
	        "Rio Declaration",
	        "Copenhagen Accord",
	        "Montreal Protocol"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Paris Agreement",
	    explanation: "The Paris Agreement is a landmark international treaty adopted in 2015 to address climate change by setting emission reduction goals.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 12,
	    question: "Which of the following is a major source of ocean pollution, often harming marine life and ecosystems?",
	    choices: [
	        "Wind erosion",
	        "Desertification",
	        "Oil spills",
	        "Volcanic eruptions",
	        "Forest fires"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Oil spills",
	    explanation: "Oil spills release large amounts of oil into marine environments, causing extensive harm to marine life and ecosystems.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 13,
	    question: "What term describes the process of converting waste materials into reusable materials, reducing the overall waste sent to landfills or incinerators?",
	    choices: [
	        "Pollution",
	        "Composting",
	        "Recycling",
	        "Incineration",
	        "Landfilling"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Recycling",
	    explanation: "Recycling involves the collection and conversion of waste materials into reusable products to reduce waste disposal and environmental impacts.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 14,
	    question: "What is the term for the gradual increase in the Earth's average temperature due to human activities, such as the burning of fossil fuels and deforestation?",
	    choices: [
	        "Acid rain",
	        "Desertification",
	        "Global warming",
	        "Ozone depletion",
	        "El Ni√±o"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Global warming",
	    explanation: "Global warming refers to the long-term increase in the Earth's average temperature, primarily caused by human-induced activities that release greenhouse gases into the atmosphere.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 15,
	    question: "What is the term for the process by which plants and trees convert carbon dioxide into oxygen and glucose using sunlight?",
	    choices: [
	        "Photosynthesis",
	        "Respiration",
	        "Fermentation",
	        "Combustion",
	        "Decomposition"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Photosynthesis",
	    explanation: "Photosynthesis is the process by which plants and trees capture carbon dioxide from the atmosphere and produce oxygen and glucose using sunlight.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 16,
	    question: "What is the primary goal of the 'Reduce, Reuse, Recycle' mantra in environmental conservation?",
	    choices: [
	        "Maximizing waste generation",
	        "Minimizing waste generation",
	        "Promoting excessive consumption",
	        "Encouraging landfill expansion",
	        "Advocating for waste incineration"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Minimizing waste generation",
	    explanation: "The 'Reduce, Reuse, Recycle' mantra aims to minimize waste generation by encouraging people to use resources efficiently, reduce consumption, and recycle materials to reduce environmental impacts.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 17,
	    question: "Which environmental issue refers to the excessive accumulation of greenhouse gases in the Earth's atmosphere, leading to a rise in global temperatures?",
	    choices: [
	        "Desertification",
	        "Deforestation",
	        "Ocean acidification",
	        "Greenhouse effect",
	        "Acid rain"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Greenhouse effect",
	    explanation: "The greenhouse effect is the phenomenon where greenhouse gases trap heat in the Earth's atmosphere, causing global temperatures to rise, a key factor in climate change.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 18,
	    question: "What is the term for the loss of a species from a particular habitat or from the entire planet?",
	    choices: [
	        "Extinction",
	        "Domestication",
	        "Migration",
	        "Predation",
	        "Hibernation"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Extinction",
	    explanation: "Extinction is the permanent disappearance of a species from a specific habitat or from the entire planet, often due to environmental changes or human activities.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 19,
	    question: "What is the primary source of energy for wind turbines used to generate electricity?",
	    choices: [
	        "Natural gas",
	        "Coal",
	        "Sunlight",
	        "Wind",
	        "Hydrogen"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Wind",
	    explanation: "Wind turbines utilize the kinetic energy of the wind to generate electricity, making wind the primary source of energy for these renewable power systems.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 20,
	    question: "Which term describes the process of converting waste materials into organic matter through decomposition, often used for soil enrichment?",
	    choices: [
	        "Incineration",
	        "Fermentation",
	        "Composting",
	        "Recycling",
	        "Landfilling"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Composting",
	    explanation: "Composting is the natural process of breaking down organic waste into nutrient-rich compost, which can be used to enhance soil quality and fertility.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 21,
	    question: "What is the primary greenhouse gas emitted during the burning of fossil fuels for energy production?",
	    choices: [
	        "Methane",
	        "Carbon dioxide (CO2)",
	        "Nitrous oxide (N2O)",
	        "Ozone (O3)",
	        "Water vapor (H2O)"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Carbon dioxide (CO2)",
	    explanation: "Carbon dioxide is the primary greenhouse gas released during the combustion of fossil fuels, contributing to climate change.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 22,
	    question: "What term describes the variety of plant and animal species in a particular habitat or on Earth as a whole?",
	    choices: [
	        "Monoculture",
	        "Deforestation",
	        "Biodiversity",
	        "Desertification",
	        "Urbanization"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Biodiversity",
	    explanation: "Biodiversity refers to the variety of plant and animal species in a specific habitat or on the planet, encompassing genetic, species, and ecosystem diversity.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 23,
	    question: "Which of the following is a renewable energy source that harnesses the heat energy from the Earth's core?",
	    choices: [
	        "Natural gas",
	        "Hydropower",
	        "Geothermal energy",
	        "Nuclear energy",
	        "Solar power"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Geothermal energy",
	    explanation: "Geothermal energy is a renewable energy source that captures heat from the Earth's core, often used for heating buildings and generating electricity.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    id: 24,
	    question: "Which environmental issue relates to the excessive accumulation of plastic waste in oceans, harming marine life and ecosystems?",
	    choices: [
	        "Land degradation",
	        "Ocean acidification",
	        "Deforestation",
	        "Plastic pollution",
	        "Eutrophication"
	    ],
	    correct_ans: "Plastic pollution",
	    explanation: "Plastic pollution refers to the extensive presence of plastic waste in oceans, leading to harm to marine life and ecosystems.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
	    "id": 25,
	    "question": "It is the most common form of unregulated commercial fishing.",
	    "choices": [
		    "Dynamite Fishing",
		    "Using Powerful Lights",
		    "Using Nets that having big holes",
		    "Overfishing",
		    "Using Electric Fishing Rods"
	    ],
	    "correct_ans": "Overfishing",
	    "explanation": "Overfishing refers to the practice of catching fish from a body of water at a rate that the species cannot replenish, leading to those species becoming underpopulated in that area. It‚Äôs a serious issue that threatens the balance of marine ecosystems and the livelihoods of communities that depend on fishing. It‚Äôs considered unregulated because it often happens in violation of laws and regulations intended to maintain sustainable fish populations. Please note that all forms of unregulated fishing are harmful and illegal, and they can have devastating effects on marine life and ecosystems. It‚Äôs important to promote and practice sustainable fishing methods to protect our oceans.",
	    "poster_name": "Manuel G. Sintos"
	},
	{
    id: 26,
    question: "What is the primary purpose of composting as an environmental practice?",
    choices: [
      "To increase the volume of landfill waste.",
      "To produce synthetic fertilizers.",
      "To convert organic waste into nutrient-rich soil.",
      "To burn organic waste for energy.",
      "To create plastic packaging materials."
    ],
    correct_ans: "To convert organic waste into nutrient-rich soil.",
    explanation: "Composting is an environmentally friendly practice that transforms organic waste into a valuable soil amendment, reducing landfill waste and enriching soil fertility.",
    poster_name: "Manuel G. Sintos"
  },
  {
    id: 27,
    question: "Which of the following is a significant consequence of deforestation in the Philippines?",
    choices: [
      "Increased biodiversity.",
      "Reduced soil erosion.",
      "Habitat loss for wildlife.",
      "Improved air quality.",
      "Enhanced water purification."
    ],
    correct_ans: "Habitat loss for wildlife.",
    explanation: "Deforestation, the clearing of forests, leads to the destruction of habitats for numerous plant and animal species, threatening biodiversity.",
    poster_name: "Manuel G. Sintos"
  },
  {
    id: 28,
    question: "What is the main environmental benefit of using renewable energy sources like solar and wind power?",
    choices: [
      "Increased air pollution.",
      "Depletion of natural resources.",
      "Reduced greenhouse gas emissions.",
      "Higher water consumption.",
      "Increased noise pollution."
    ],
    correct_ans: "Reduced greenhouse gas emissions.",
    explanation: "Renewable energy sources, such as solar and wind power, produce electricity without emitting greenhouse gases, helping to mitigate climate change.",
    poster_name: "Manuel G. Sintos"
  },
  {
    id: 29,
    question: "Which of the following practices is most effective in reducing the amount of waste sent to landfills?",
    choices: [
      "Incineration of all waste.",
      "Open dumping of waste.",
      "Proper waste segregation and recycling.",
      "Exporting waste to other countries.",
      "Burying waste in the ground."
    ],
    correct_ans: "Proper waste segregation and recycling.",
    explanation: "Proper waste segregation and recycling are crucial for reducing the volume of waste sent to landfills by diverting recyclable materials for reuse.",
    poster_name: "Manuel G. Sintos"
  },
  {
    id: 30,
    question: "What is the term for the process where excessive nutrients in water bodies lead to algal blooms and oxygen depletion, harming aquatic life?",
    choices: [
      "Eutrophication",
      "Desertification",
      "Acidification",
      "Deforestation",
      "Urbanization"
    ],
    correct_ans: "Eutrophication",
    explanation: "Eutrophication occurs when excessive nutrients, often from agricultural runoff, enter water bodies, causing algal blooms that deplete oxygen and harm aquatic life.",
    poster_name: "Manuel G. Sintos"
  },
  {
    id: 31,
    question: "Which of the following is a key objective of the Convention on Biological Diversity (CBD)?",
    choices: [
      "To promote the use of single-use plastics.",
      "To increase greenhouse gas emissions.",
      "To conserve biological diversity and promote its sustainable use.",
      "To encourage deforestation for agriculture.",
      "To regulate international trade in fossil fuels."
    ],
    correct_ans: "To conserve biological diversity and promote its sustainable use.",
    explanation: "The Convention on Biological Diversity (CBD) aims to conserve biological diversity, promote its sustainable use, and ensure the fair and equitable sharing of benefits from genetic resources.",
    poster_name: "Manuel G. Sintos"
  },
  {
    id: 32,
    question: "What is the primary environmental concern addressed by Republic Act No. 8749, also known as the Philippine Clean Air Act?",
    choices: [
      "Water pollution",
      "Solid waste management",
      "Air pollution",
      "Deforestation",
      "Soil erosion"
    ],
    correct_ans: "Air pollution",
    explanation: "Republic Act No. 8749, the Philippine Clean Air Act, primarily addresses air pollution by setting standards for air quality and regulating emissions from various sources.",
    poster_name: "Manuel G. Sintos"
  },
  {
    id: 33,
    question: "Which of the following is a direct consequence of overfishing in marine ecosystems?",
    choices: [
      "Increased fish populations.",
      "Improved water quality.",
      "Depletion of fish stocks and biodiversity loss.",
      "Enhanced coral reef growth.",
      "Reduced ocean temperatures."
    ],
    correct_ans: "Depletion of fish stocks and biodiversity loss.",
    explanation: "Overfishing leads to the decline of fish populations and disrupts the balance of marine ecosystems, causing biodiversity loss.",
    poster_name: "Manuel G. Sintos"
  },
  {
    id: 34,
    question: "What is the term for the variety of life forms, including plants, animals, and microorganisms, in a particular habitat or ecosystem?",
    choices: [
      "Deforestation",
      "Biodiversity",
      "Desertification",
      "Urbanization",
      "Pollution"
    ],
    correct_ans: "Biodiversity",
    explanation: "Biodiversity refers to the variety of life forms in a given area, encompassing genetic, species, and ecosystem diversity.",
    poster_name: "Manuel G. Sintos"
  },
  {
    id: 35,
    question: "Which of the following is a renewable energy source that utilizes heat from the Earth's interior?",
    choices: [
        "Solar power",
        "Wind power",
        "Geothermal energy",
        "Coal",
        "Natural gas"
    ],
    correct_ans: "Geothermal energy",
    explanation: "Geothermal energy harnesses heat from the Earth's core to generate electricity or provide heating.",
    poster_name: "Manuel G. Sintos"
  },
  {
    id: 36,
    question: "What is the term for the process of breaking down organic waste into nutrient-rich material for soil improvement?",
    choices: [
        "Incineration",
        "Landfilling",
        "Composting",
        "Recycling",
        "Mining"
    ],
    correct_ans: "Composting",
    explanation: "Composting is the process of decomposing organic matter to create a nutrient-rich soil amendment.",
    poster_name: "Manuel G. Sintos"
  },
  {
    id: 37,
    question: "What is the term for the excessive and unsustainable harvesting of fish from the ocean?",
    choices: [
        "Aquaculture",
        "Overfishing",
        "Marine conservation",
        "Sustainable fishing",
        "Fish farming"
    ],
    correct_ans: "Overfishing",
    explanation: "Overfishing occurs when fish are caught at a rate faster than they can reproduce, leading to depleted populations.",
    poster_name: "Manuel G. Sintos"
  },
  {
    id: 38,
    question: "What is the name of the international agreement that aims to reduce greenhouse gas emissions and limit global warming?",
    choices: [
        "Montreal Protocol",
        "Kyoto Protocol",
        "Paris Agreement",
        "Ramsar Convention",
        "Basel Convention"
    ],
    correct_ans: "Paris Agreement",
    explanation: "The Paris Agreement is a global treaty that aims to combat climate change by reducing greenhouse gas emissions.",
    poster_name: "Manuel G. Sintos"
  },
  {
    id: 39,
    question: "What is the term for the process where pollutants, such as sulfur dioxide and nitrogen oxides, mix with atmospheric moisture and fall to the Earth as acidic precipitation?",
    choices: [
        "Eutrophication",
        "Acid rain",
        "Desertification",
        "Deforestation",
        "Ozone depletion"
    ],
    correct_ans: "Acid rain",
    explanation: "Acid rain is the phenomenon where pollutants like sulfur dioxide and nitrogen oxides mix with atmospheric moisture, resulting in acidic precipitation that harms ecosystems.",
    poster_name: "Manuel G. Sintos"
  },
];